smokymountains.com 2018-01-27

# SmokyMountains.com Privacy Policy - Please Read

**Privacy Policy**  
This policy was last updated and posted in June 2013. It governs the privacy policy of our Website, [http://smokymountains.com](http://smokymountains.com/), owned and operated by Smoky Mountains, LLC.

**Definitions**  
“Non-Personal Information” is information that is in no way personally identifiable and that is obtained automatically through your simple use of our Website with a web browser.  
“Personally Identifiable Information” is non-public information that is personally identifiable and obtained in connection with providing a product or service to you. It may include information such as your name, address, phone number, and other related information you provide to us.

**Our Commitment to Your Privacy  
**This Privacy Policy tells you what Personally Identifiable Information we may collect from you, how we may share this information, and how you can limit our sharing of your information.

Smoky Mountains, LLC is committed to the security and privacy of all our clients. We take your privacy seriously, and we will work with you to ensure that you have an enjoyable shopping experience, but that you do so in a safe and secure online environment.

Smoky Mountains, LLC and its affiliates are committed to respecting your privacy and recognize the need for appropriate protection and management of your Personally Identifiable Information you share with us.

As a part of our commitment to your privacy, we support and adhere to the guidelines and practices adopted by the Direct Marketing Association Privacy Promise to consumers. Accordingly, we have agreed to (1) provide customers with notice of their ability to opt out of information exchanges with other marketers; (2) honor customer requests not to have their information transferred to others for marketing purposes; and (3) accept and honor customer requests not to receive solicitations from any of our brands.

**Links to Other Websites**  
Our Website may contain links to other websites that are not under our direct control. These websites may have their own policies regarding privacy. We have no control of or responsibility for linked websites and provide these links solely for the convenience and information of our visitors. You access such linked websites at your own risk. These websites are not subject to this Privacy Policy. You should check the privacy policies, if any, of those individual websites to see how the operators of those third-party websites will utilize your personal information. In addition, these websites may contain a link to websites of our affiliates. The websites of our affiliates are not subject to this Privacy Policy, and you should check their individual privacy policies to see how the operators of such websites will utilize your personal information.

**What Information We May Collect  
**Generally, our customers and investors can visit our Website without providing or revealing any personal or Personally Identifiable Information. We receive and store certain types of information whenever visitors interact with our Website. We may track the Internet domain address from which our visitors visit our Website and analyze this data for trends and statistics. Unless a visitor to our Website voluntarily provides Personally Identifiable Information to us, each individual customer remains anonymous.

We receive and may store certain Personally Identifiable Information that our visitors enter when visiting our website or provide to us in other ways. For instance, we collect the information you provide to us when you place an order, register with us, send an email or call us, enter a sweepstakes or contest, subscribe to a service, enroll in a club, request to receive a catalog, or participate in a promotion. This information may include your name, shipping/billing address, telephone number, email address, credit card information, product purchases, birth date, gender, occupation, personal interests, and other similar personal or preference data that you provide to us. It may also include information you submit about other people such as the name and address of a gift recipient. Whether or not you provide such information to us is completely your own choice.

**How We Use Your Information  
**We use the personal and/or Personally Identifiable Information you provide for our internal purposes, such as confirming and tracking your order, analyzing trends and statistics, informing you of our new products (including products of our affiliates), services and offers, and providing you with information about us and our products.

From time to time, we may also work with other organizations that we believe are trustworthy and offer products or services that may be of interest to you. In such instances, we might share limited information (such as your name and postal address) that we have collected from you, including Personally Identifiable Information, so that such organizations may contact you with offers that may interest you. However, we will not share your information with these organizations if you have requested that we refrain from doing so.

To serve you better, we may combine the information you give us online, through our catalogs, and from our retail locations; publicly available information and information we receive from others. We use that combined information to enhance and personalize your experience with us, to communicate with you about our products and events that may be of interest to you, and for other promotional purposes.

Also, we may contract with third-party service providers to provide certain services for our business, such as credit card processing, computer system services, shipping, data management, advertisements, or promotional services. We provide the information needed for these service providers to perform these services. The information we provide may include some of our customers’ personal and Personally Identifiable Information. However, these service providers are not authorized to use any of the information we share with them for any purposes other than to provide services to us.

We may share information that we have collected with governmental agencies and other organizations assisting us in fraud prevention or for investigative purposes. We may do so when permitted or mandated by law; trying to protect against or prevent fraud; attempting to prevent unauthorized or improper transactions; or investigating fraud or improper conduct that has already taken place. In these instances, the information is not provided to these agencies or organizations for marketing or any other unrelated purposes.

Additionally, we may share your email address, name, telephone number, and postal address within the Smoky Mountains, LLC family of businesses. Also, when you purchase from us through our catalogs or Websites we may need to contact you via phone, email, or mail to address issues specific to your order, even if you have opted not to receive communications from us.

From time to time we may also market certain third-party services through our Website. Should you choose to accept an offer from a third-party, we will pass your relevant Personally Identifiable Information, including your name, postal address, credit/debit card number and any other required billing information to that specific third-party.

Finally, if some or all of the business assets of any our companies are sold or transferred; we generally would transfer the corresponding information regarding our customers and visitors to the purchaser. We also may retain a copy of that information.

**Changes to Your Information**  
You may update your registered Personally Identifiable Information at any time. This includes your name, password, email, and postal address. You may also manage your mailing preferences and email formats.  If at any time you would like us to update your Personally Identifiable Information or remove you from our email or postal mailing lists, or if you need assistance with the modification of your information, send us an email with your request.

**Opting Out of Sharing Information**  
You may opt out of future unaffiliated third-party disclosures of your information. Such opt-out will not affect disclosures otherwise permitted by law including but not limited to: (i) disclosures to affiliates, (ii) disclosures to third-party service providers who provide certain services for our business, such as credit card processing, computer system services, shipping, data management, or promotional services, (iii) disclosures to third parties as necessary to fulfill your requests, (iv) disclosures to governmental agencies or law enforcement departments or otherwise required to be made under applicable law, (v) previously completed disclosures to third parties, or (vi) disclosures to third parties in connection with subsequent contests or promotions you may choose to enter, or third-party offers you may choose to accept.

**Protecting Your Child’s Privacy**  
Our Website is not designed for use by anyone under the age of 18 (child), though we realize we may have users under this age. We do not verify the age of our users nor do we have any liability for verifying a user’s age. If you are under the age of 18, please seek the permission of a parent or guardian before placing an order. If you are a parent or guardian and believe your child is using our Website, please contact us. If children submit information to us, and we know that the individuals submitting the information are indeed children, we will delete the information as soon as we discover it. We will not use the information for any purpose, and we will not disclose the information to third parties.

**Our Email Policy**  
Smoky Mountains, LLC and our affiliates all fully comply with international laws regarding SPAM. You can always opt out of receipt of further email correspondence from us. We will not sell, rent, or trade your email address to any unaffiliated third-party without your permission. We believe that your email address is personal and should be kept that way. We use your email address to provide better customer service, to facilitate your transactions with our third-party marketing partners, and to be able to inform you of the Internet offers and promotions from us or our affiliates.

**Our Security Policy**  
Because we all benefit from secure online shopping, we have taken steps to build and manage a system that you can use with confidence. We use sophisticated encryption and authentication tools to protect the security of the Personally Identifiable Information that you share with us. If sensitive data is collected through this Website, we will encrypt your Personally Identifiable Information before it travels over the Internet using industry standards for secure online transactions. The Personally Identifiable Information you provide to us is preserved behind a firewall, instead of being directly connected to the Internet. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Once we receive your transmission, we have appropriate security measures in place within our physical facilities to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of the Personally Identifiable Information you have provided to us.

We urge you to keep your password for our Website in a safe place and not divulge it to anyone. Also remember to sign off your account and close your browser window when you have finished your visit to our Website. This is to ensure that others cannot access your account, especially if you are sharing a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place such as a library or Internet cafe.

**Use of Payment Sources**  
To make a purchase through our Website, you will have to provide a payment source, such as a credit card. We use third-party billing services and HAVE NO CONTROL over these services. We will use our best efforts to make sure that your payment source is kept STRICTLY CONFIDENTIAL by using only third-party billing services that use industry-standard technologies to protect your payment source from unauthorized use. However, you understand and agree that we are in no way responsible for any misuse of your payment source.

**Cookies**  
Our Website may send a “cookie” to your computer. A cookie is a small piece of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer’s hard drive. A cookie cannot read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. Cookies do not damage your system. We use cookies to identify which areas of our site you have visited, so the next time you visit the site, we can better personalize the content that you see on our Website. In addition, Cookies may be used to serve relevant advertisements and emails to you after you leave our site. Most browser software can be set to reject Cookies. However, if you reject our Cookies, certain functionality on our Website may not work correctly or at all. We do not place Personally Identifiable Information in Cookies.

**Google Remarketing & AdRoll Retargeting**  
Smoky Mountains LLC and its third-party vendors use cookies to serve you relevant ads based on your interactions with our site. The ads, which are served by third-party vendors including Google and AdRoll, are displayed on a variety of sites across the Internet.  
If you wish to opt out of Google Remarketing, simply visit: <http://www.google.com/settings/ads/>  
If you wish to opt out of AdRoll Retargeting, simply visit: <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>

**Web Beacons**  
We may also use Web Beacons to collect Non-Personal Information about your use of our Website and the websites of selected sponsors and advertisers, and your use of special promotions or newsletters. The information collected by Web Beacons (a) allows us to statistically monitor how many people open our emails and (b) for what purposes these actions are being taken. Our Web Beacons are not used to track your activity outside of our Websites or those of our sponsors’. We do not link Non-Personal Information from Web Beacons to Personally Identifiable Information without your permission.

**Changes to Our Privacy Policy  
**From time to time, our privacy and security practices may change. If we modify our Privacy Policy, in whole or in part, to address these changes, we will indicate when such changes are made by changing the “Last Updated” date at the beginning of this Privacy Policy. Those changes will be effective as of the Last Updated date. The new policy will apply to all current and past users of our Website and will replace any prior policies that are inconsistent. We may change or add to this Privacy Policy, so we encourage you to review it periodically.

**Questions About Our Privacy Policy**  
To help us improve our privacy and security policies and practices, please send us your questions and feedback using the Contact Us and Feedback forms on our Website.
